The Register to the Betsy Jolas Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 1958-2006; Series I
  - Music by Jolas, 1
    - Chamber music, 4
      - Petite Sonnerie de Juin, 1986; 1 page; Thematic sketch in ink, autographed. (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Points d'aube: pour alto et 13 instruments à vent, 2 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Points d'aube: pour alto et 13 instruments à vent, 33 pages; Holograph in ink. Dedicated to Serge Collot, "Paris 1 .2. 68, 20. 2. 69" (incomplete). (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Points d'aube, 57 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. "1e version et corrections (incompletes), Paris 1. 2. 68." (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Points d'aube: pour alto et 13 instruments a vent, 58 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil, "Paris 1. 2. 68." (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Points d'aube: pour alto et 13 instruments a vent, 55 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Post Scriptum pour Henri, 1 page; Photocopy of manuscript. For clarinet, violin, viola, and violoncello. "Original offert á Henri Dutilleaux pour ses 90 ans (2006), Chérence 24 12 2005." (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Puer apud magistros exercentur (Cicéron), 17 pages; Holograph in pencil and photocopy of manuscript with annotations. For 2 alto saxophones, "3 Octobre 2007." (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Puer apud magistros exercentur, 7 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Quatuor I, 18 pages; Holograph in ink, "Paris 16. 12. 56." (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Quatuor III: 9 études, 21 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Paris le 7 Septembre 1973." Includes performance notes. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Quatuor III: 9 études, 22 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Quatuor III: 9 études, 21 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Quatuor III: 9 études, 20 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Quatuor IV: "menus propos", 4 pages; Proof with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Quatuor IV: "menus propos", 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Paris le 26. 10. 88." (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Quatuor V, 30 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "Commande de ProQuartet, Chérence le 12 Aout 1994." (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Quatuor V
      - Quatuor V, 30 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 4)
        Standard Title: Quatuor V
      - Quatuor V, 4 pages; Holograph in pencil, "1ere esquisse." (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Quartet, no. 5, strings, 6 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil and photocopy of manuscript; includes notes. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Quatuor V: pour Quatuor à Cordes, 37 pages; Proof with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Quatuor VI: "avec clarinette", 12 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Pour le 10e anniversaire de l'ensemble FA, Chérence le 23 Aout 1997." (Box 9, Folder 6)
        Standard Title: Quatuor VI
      - Quatuor VI, 2 pages; Holograph in pencil, "première esquisse." (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - "Quoth the raven…": pour clarinette et piano, 1993; 6 pages; Holograph in pencil and ink. (Box 9, Folder 7)
        Standard Title: Quoth the Raven
      - Quoth the raven, 3 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil; contains manuscript sketches. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Remember, 5 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil; includes manuscript sketches. Dedicated to Jean Pierre Guézec 1934-1971. "Paris 31. 3. 71, 25. 4. 71." (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Sonata sopra "et sola facta", 9 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. Includes 1 page of miscellaneous manuscript. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Sonata sopra "et sola facta", 7 pages; Holograph in pencil, for violin, clarinet, and piano. Includes sketches. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Sonata à 8, 19 pages; Manuscript sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Sonate à trois, 19 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil. "Paris, 5. 4. 56." (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Suite pour piano, alto et flute, 13 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "A Geneviève Noufflard (flute) jouer ensemble, the viola part for me". "New York, Feb 9 1946." (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Suite pour piano, alto et flute, 11 pages; Holograph in ink; includes sketches. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Suite en canons: pour trois violons, 1951; 4 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Teletalks, 2008; 25 pages; Computer generated score with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Theme and variations: for horn, clarinet, violin and cello, 13 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Bennington October 1945." (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Trifolium: pour flûte et piano, 19 pages; Photocopy of manuscript. Dedicated to Claude, "Paris, 7 Mars 1947." (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Trio: "Les Heures", 35 pages; Holograph in pencil. For violin, viola, and violoncello. "Commande de l'Etat pour les 25 ans du Trio à cordes de Paris." "Chérence le 28 Aout 1990." (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Trio: "Les Heures" pour violon, alto et violoncelle, 22 pages; Proof with annotations in pencil (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Trio (88): piano violon violoncelle, 37 pages; Holograph in pencil; includes notes and index cards (sketches). "Commissioned by the Walter Naumburg Foundation for the Mannes Trio." "Chérence le 28. 12. 88." (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Solo instrumental music, 5
      - B for Sonata, 1973; 20 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - B for Sonata, 1973; 30 pages; Printed score with annotations in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - B for Sonata, 15 pages; Manuscript sketches in ink and pencil. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Calling E.C., 1982; 3 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Chanson d'Approche, 1972; 4 pages; Transparency score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Episode 1 for Flute Solo, 1963-1965; 2 pages; Photocopied sketches with post-it notes in pencil (Box 10, Folder 7)
        Standard Title: Episode, no. 1
      - Episode, 1 page; Photocopy of manuscript cut in sections and pasted on a larger piece of paper. Contains annotations in pencil. "Maquette edition et 1er calque." (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episode: pour flûte seule, 4 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to Severino Grazzeloni. "Version definitive, Paris, 15. 1. 64." (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episode: pour flûte seule, 4 pages; Holograph in ink. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episodes, no.1, flute, 1 page; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episodes, no.1, flute, 3 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episode 1 pour flûte, elem. analyse, 37 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes 3 pages of sketches for an unfinished project (1e project). (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Episode second: Ohne Worte pour flûte seule, 1977; 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes 2 pages of inserts. "Paris, 12. 2. 1977". (Box 9, Folder 19)
        Standard Title: Episode, no. 2
      - Ohne worte: nouvel Episode pour flûte, 1977; 3 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes manuscript sketches. "Paris, 3. 2. 1977." (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Episode second: Ohne worte, 3 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Episode troisième: pour trompette en ut, 1981; 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Paris le 4. 1. 82; Dedicated to Antoine [Illouz]." (Box 9, Folder 20)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 3
      - Episode troisième: pour trompette, 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "a Antoine, 1e esquisse." (Box 9, Folder 20)
        Standard Title: Episode, no. 3
      - Episode 4e: pour saxophone tenor, 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Paris le 25. 9. 83." (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Episode 4e: pour saxophone ténor seul, 5 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Episode 4e, 1983, 3 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Episode quatrieme: pour saxophone ténor seul, 6 pages; Proof with annotations. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Episode cinquième: pour violoncelle seul, 1983; 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Chérence le 22 Juillet 1983." (Box 9, Folder 21)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 5
      - Episode sixième: pour alto seul, 1984; 6 pages; Proof with annotations and notes. "Paris, le 12. 3. 1984". (Box 9, Folder 22)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 6
      - Episode sixième pour alto, 1984; 7 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Episode septième pour guitare électrique, 1984; 6 pages; Holograph score in pencil with annotations and sketches. (Box 9, Folder 23)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 7
      - Episode huitième pour contrebasse, 1984; 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes 3 pages of notes. "1e version." (Box 9, Folder 24)
        Standard title: Episode, No. 8
      - Episode 8e pour contrebasse, 1984; 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Paris le 10 Décembre 1984." (Box 9, Folder 24)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 8
      - Episode huitième pour contrebasse, 1984; 4 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Paris le 10 Décembre 1984." (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Episode 9e "Fortem magnum coloratum" pour clarinette en si bémol, 1990; 2 pages; Holograph in pencil. Dedicated to Paul Rovsing Olsen, "Paris le 28. 9. 90." Manuscript sketches on verso. "Version definitive." (Box 9, Folder 25)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 9
      - Episode 9e: "Fortem magnum coloratum" pour clarinette en si bémol, 1990; 1 page; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "2e version Paris le 28. 9. 90." (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Episode 9e: "Fortem magnum coloratum" pour clarinette en si bémol, 1990; 1 page; Photocopy of manuscript. "1e version creation Lerchenberg Aout 90, Paris le 29. 3. 90." (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Episode 10e '"e sempre la notte va...", 2000; 2 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 26)
        Standard Title: Episode, No. 10
      - Episode 10e "e sempre la notte va...", 2000; 2 pages; Photocopied holograph score with pencil annotations. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Etudes Aperçues, 1992; 8 pages; Photocopied holograph score with pencil annotations. Includes correspondence with Thierry Miroglio. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Etudes Aperçues, 1992; 7 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "Boston 31 10 92" (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Exercises: "Prelude" and "Themes for the four movements of a sonata", 1944; 4 pages; Sketches in pencil. Prelude for keyboard: "Allegro molto." Theme sketches for keyboard: "Allegro," "Andante," "Scherzo," "Finale - presto." (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - A Fancy for Anssi, 2010; 2 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - For Organ: Toccata, 1944; 6 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "For inauguration of the New North Bennington Baptist chuch organ." (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Fusain pour un Flûtiste, 1971; 4 pages; Holograph in ink. "Paris, Décembre 1971." (Box 9, Folder 31)
        Standard Title: Fusain
      - Fusain pour un Flûtiste, 1971; 6 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Fusain pour un Flûtiste, 1971-1972; 2 pages; For piccolo/bass flute, and voice. Two proofs of first pages. Note on score in pen. (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Fusain, 1971; 12 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes 5 pages of photocopied note combinations. (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Génerique, 1967; 3 pages; Manuscript sketches in pen and pencil (Box 9, Folder 41)
        Standard Title: Tranche
      - Leçons du Petit Jour, 2007; 27 pages; Printed score photocopy with (copied pencil) and pen annotations (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Leçons du Petit Jour, 2007; 12 pages; Holograph score in pencil (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Morning Thoughts, 2009; 4 pages; Holograph score in pencil (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Morning Thoughts, 1 page; Manuscript sketch in pencil (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Musique du Jour pour Orgue, 8 pages; Photocopied score with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Musique du Jour pour Orgue, 1976; 9 pages; Printed score with annotations. "Exemplaire portant nos registration." "Chereuce le 2.1.1976" (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Musique du Jour pour Orgue, 1976; 8 pages; Printed score. "Chereuce le 2.1.1976" (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Nocturne, 1943; 3 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - O Bach, 2007; 6 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - O Bach, 7 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - O Bach!, 2007; 9 pages; Photocopied holograph score with annotations in pencil. Interspersed holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - O Bach...!, 2007; 4 pages; Two copies of typed performance instructions. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - O Bach, 6 pages; Sketches in pencil. "Toccata-Ricercar in memoriam J.S." (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Petite Fantasie pour Léo, 2000; 1 page; Holograph in pencil, for flute. (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Pièce pour St Germain, 11 pages; Sketches in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Pièce Pour, 1997; 4 pages; Manuscript score in pencil. "Paris le 25 Janvier 1997" (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Pièce Pour, 6 pages; Manuscript sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Postlude, 6 pages; Sketches in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Postlude, 2006; 8 pages; Photocopies (2) of published score with annotations. (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Postlude, 2005; 3 pages; Photocopy of holograph score with annotations in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Postlude, 2005; 3 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Signets, 1987; 4 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Sonata, viola, 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 39)
        Standard Title: Sonate
      - Sonate pour alto seul, 1954; 7 pages; Holograph in ink and photocopy of manuscript with pencil annotations. "Paris, 12. 11. 54." (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Sonatina, 1944; 3 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Suite pour piano, 1955; 4 pages; Printed score with pencil annotations. Movements III ("Il fait dimanche sur la mer"), IV ("Je suis parti clair et leger le corps enveloppe de vent et de lumiere"), and the opening of V ("Le jours de franc soleil et de belle saison"). (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Tango Si, 1984; 2 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "Cherence le 2 Aout 1984." (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Tranche pour harpe seule, 1967; 8 pages; Photocopy of manuscript score with pencil annotations and accompanying description. (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Trois Études Campanaires, 1980; 6 pages; Holograph score in pencil (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Music for chorus with accompaniment, 6
      - Autres enfantillages: text materials, 20 pages; Materials from a word game that Betsy Jolas used in compiling the text, with her explanatory note. (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Autres enfantillages, 2000; 13 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Commande de la ville de Chateauroux; ou l'art d'ètre grand-mére; pour choeur d'enfants et clarinette oblige ou choeur d'enfants a capella (débuts et fins marque's de double barres). Textes de Betsy Jolas, realises avec le concours de Léo et ses amis au cours de jeux de 'petits papiers.'" (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Autres enfantillages, 9 pages; Holograph in pencil. Includes sketches. "Textes de Betsy Jolas, realises avec le concours de Léo et ses amis au cours de jeux de 'petits papiers.'" (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie, 2001; 4 pages; Lecture notes in pencil: "Notes for a lecture introducing the premiere..." (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestra), 2001; 37 pages; Published score with annotations in pencil and ink. Dedicated to Jay Gottlieb; "Citations de Shakespeare, Victor Hugo et anonymes; Durée: ca 31'; Commande de 'Octobre en Normandie'; Paris le 30 avril 2001." (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 2001; 61 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. Includes 3 pages of text. Dedicated to Jay Gottlieb; "Durée: ca 31', Citations de Shakespeare, Victor Hugo et anonymes; Commande de 'Octobre en Normandie'; Paris le 30 avril 2001." (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour Piano et Choeur (sans orchestre); Holograph of corrections in pencil. Includes text by Betsy Jolas about the piece in English and French. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 22 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 2000; 5 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil, part III. "Durée: ca 3' 30"; Citations de Victor Hugo et Shakespeare; Paris le 26 mars 2000" (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Durée: ca 3' 30"; citations de Victor Hugo et Shakespeare, 2e version avant Concerto; Paris le 26 mars 2000." (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 2 pages; Holograph score in pencil. Contains 3 pages of photocopies of manuscript. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 4 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "Citations de Victor Hugo et Shakespeare; Chérence le 23 Mars 2000." (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 5 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Concerto-Fantaisie: "O Night, Oh..." pour piano et choeur (sans orchestre), 12 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. Includes 19 pages of notes (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Enfantillages: pour choeur feminin, 2000; 4 pages; Proof with annotations. Flute part only. "Version avec Flûte oblige; Dedicated to Claire; 1956 – Chérence le 8 avril 2000." (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Enfantillages: pour choeur feminin, 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Version avec Flûte oblige; Chérence le 8 avril 2000." (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Happy Birthday Arts Flo, 1 page; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Mass: for women's chorus, soli and orchestra, 1945; 46 pages; Photocopy of manuscript. Score for chorus and instruments. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Mass: for women's chorus, soli and orchestra, 1945; 27 pages; Photocopy of manuscript. Score for chorus and piano. (Box 11, Folder 1B)
      - Motet II, 1965; 45 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil and ink. Includes 1 page of text and 1 page of notes."Pour choeur mixte à 12 voix et orchestre de chambre, 1e version." (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Motet II, 28 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. "Version définitive, 1965-1983; Paris Decembre 1965, Révision 1983". (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Motet II, 1965; 17 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil and ink (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Motet III, 17 pages; Holograph sketches in ink and pencil. Fragments of parts. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Motet III, 2 pages; Holograph score in pencil. Theorbo part. Includes signed letter from BJ to Liz Kenney. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Motet III, 70 pages; Miscellaneous notes and outlines. Includes 6 pages of photocopies and notes about vocal ranges. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Motet III, 30 pages; Computer printout and photocopies of several libretti in French and Latin. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Motet III, 1998; 51 pages; Holograph score in pencil. For 5 vocal soloists, choir, and orchestra. "D'après "De rerum natura" Lucrèce; Rome Chérence Mars Avril 1999." (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Motet III, 1998; 47 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. For 5 vocal soloists, choir, and orchestra. "D'après "De rerum natura" Lucrèce; Rome Chérence Mars Avril 1999." (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Motet III, 38 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Third section not complete. (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Motet III, 11 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. "Secunda pars." (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Motet III, 5 pages; Manuscript sketches in pencil. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - L'Oeil égaré dans les plis de l'obéissance au vent, 10 pages; Libretto in English. translated by Tina Jolas. Typed with corrections in pencil. Includes 2 pages of notes. (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - L'Oeil égaré dans les plis de l'obéissance au vent, 5 pages; Holograph score in ink. Possible replacement pages for pages 37, 40, 47, 54, and 83 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - L'Oeil égaré dans les plis de l'obéissance au vent, 40 pages; Holograph score in ink with annotations in pencil. "1e version annotée; Reduction piano et chant." (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - L'Oeil égaré dans les plis de l'obéissance au vent, 105 pages; Holograph score in ink with annotations in pencil. "Cantate radiophonique pour soprano, contralto, baryton, choeur mixte et quinze instrumentistes; texts de Victor Hugo, musique de Betsy Jolas, adaptation et realization d'Alain Trutat; Paris le 3.5.61" (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Works for unaccompanied chorus, 7
      - Arbres, 23 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil and photocopy of manuscript with annotations in ink and pencil. Includes 1 page of text. "Poéms d'André du Bouchet; Arbres – Et le reste à l'avenant; durée d'execution ca: 4'00; Paris Novembre 1950; Et le reste à l'avenant: durée d'execution ca: 6' 05", Dec 1951." (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Cantique des cantiques, 44 pages; Holograph in ink and copy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. For a capella chorus. "1e version de Diurnes." (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Le Vent Coule et s'en Va, 3 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Le vent coule et sén va (1954) – Savez vous qui est mon ami? (1956); Le vent coule et sén va: poème de Nazim Hikmet; Savez vous qui est mon ami?: texte et musique Betsy Jolas." (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - A dormant chant du dormant, 2000; 7 pages; Holograph score in pencil. "Citations de Victor Hugo et Shakespeare; durée: ca 5' 40", 2e version avant concerto; Paris le 15 Mars 2000 (revu le 28 Mars)." (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Depuis six mille ans la guerre, 4 pages; Holograph in ink. In folder with cover sheet: Choeurs politiques (1951-54). (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Diurnes, 28 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Femme en son Jardin, 2009; 15 pages; Holograph score in pencil (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Femme en son Jardin, 2009; 34 pages; Sketches in pencil. Includes printed score excerpts for "Chanson d'Approche," "Mon Ami," "Piece pour," "Stances," "B for Sonata," and "Frauenleibe." (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Für Celia affettuoso, 9 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Lamentationes, 2009; 5 pages; Holograph score for four voices in pencil. Includes tessitura layout. (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Lamentations, 2009; 6 pages; Holograph score for five voices in pencil (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - (Lamentations [?]) - Monsieur Le Soleil (comptine), 2009; 7 pages; Holograph score in pencil. Includes 2-voice, 1-voice, and canon versions. (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Liberez Henri Martin, 1953; 1 page; Holograph in ink. In folder with cover sheet: Choeurs politiques (1951-54). (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Magnificat, 22 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations and 7 parts. "Paris 12-12-55." (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Motet No.1 "To Everything There is a Season", 1946; 9 pages; Photocopy of score and 1 page of handwritten text in pen. (Box 12, Folder 22)
        Standard Title: Motet I - To Everything, There is a Season